# Ivan Zolin

+7 (906) 936 3300 - zolin.work@yandex.ru - linkedin.com/in/ivan-zolin - github.com/IMZolin

#### **SUMMARY**

SPbSTU graduate, Bachelor's Degree 2024. Has **2+ years** of programming experience, **Data Science & Research Experience**. Experience: Laboratory at SPbSTU, **finished 5+ ML research projects**. I reached **the Grand-Final of the Russian Scientific Competition** by Melnichenko, participated in conferences and competitions, and have **publications and achievements**. Technical skills: Python, C/C++, PyTorch, OpenCV, ML, DL, Computer Vision, NLP.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** Python, C/C++ (parallel computing, structural design patterns), SQL, JavaScript, Tex **Libraries and Tools:** PyTorch, OpenCV, Sklearn, Pandas, Numpy, matplotlib, Git, Docker, Linux, Django, ReactJs, Redis, PostgreSQL, BeautifulSoup, aiogram

**Knowledge:** Machine learning, Deep learning, Statistics, Advanced mathematics, Optimization methods, Algorithms and Data structures

alla Data structures

Languages: Russian(Native), English(Intermediate, B1)

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Data Scientist**

Laboratory of Molecular Neurodegeneration at SPbSTU, Saint-Petersburg, Russia

April 2023 - Present

- Development of a **neural network (UNet, PyTorch)** denoising (noise reduction) for **3D images** obtained from a microscope. Average **PSNR: 40-46 dB** depending on noise level.
- Development of **automatic segmentation** of calibration samples (spheres) from a microscope (**OpenCV**). **Accelerated** the segmentation process by **hundreds of times**.
- Creating a **web service** (ReactJS, Django, Docker, Redis, Nginx) to **improve the quality of images** from a microscope (with built-in ML methods and NN models).Demo
- Creating an **AI assistant** for biological laboratories at <u>Blue Sky Research</u> based on a **RAG system**, which enables **answering scientific questions** (literature sources) and **grant organization** (grant websites), implemented as a Telegram bot.

## Tech Lead, Software developer

Partner Finder (startup), Saint-Petersburg, Russia

February 2023 - August 2023

- Creating a search engine in the system for business offers (scikit-learn, nltk).
- Creating a recommendation system, combining it with other recommendations based on user information.
- Parsing an analog's site getting data for training (ads and users) in json format.

# Fullstack developer

Inream (startup), Saint-Petersburg, Russia

November 2022 - December 2022

• Make upload files (the current HTML page) to create personalized jobs based on them. Learn about deploying the app on Heroku.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Peter the Great St. Petersburg Polytechnic University (SPbSTU)

Bachelor's Degree in Applied Mathematics and Computer Science, GPA: 4.53/5.00

Saint-Petersburg, Russia

August 2020 - June 2024

## **PROJECTS**

• The problem of the optimal area of the raft when turning,

Technologies: Optimization methods, Python, numpy, pygame, LaTEX.

**Multidimensional minimization** by the Zoitendijk method of a rectangular raft with **two changeable projections** shaped like isosceles triangles. **GitHub Demo** 

• ToDo List Telegram bot (ru, en),

Technologies: Python, SQL, Docker, aiogram, pewee, PostgreSQL.

Telegram bot for creating, editing and deleting tasks. Supports **two languages: Russian and English**. The task consists of a description, date, time, periodicity, and files. <u>GitHub</u>

## **PUBLICATIONS AND ACHIEVEMENTS**

- "Web service for confocal microscope point scattering function calculation and image deconvolution", CB&AI Computational biology and artificial intelligence for personalized medicine. Link
- The Grand-final of the Andrey Melnichenko Russian Science Competition Link
- Participation in the conference "Polytechnic for Life Sciences" Link